

40 Allées de Tourny, 33000 Bordeaux, France

🛮 (+33)6 16 24 58 68 | 🗷 thomas.lentali@gmail.com | 🛅 thomas-lentali | 🗘 tlentali | 💃 tlentali | 🖹 tlentali

Summary

Data Scientist with 5+ years experience specializing in machine learning applied to a broad-spectrum of field like search engine relevancy, product recommandation, bot detection, NLP, computer vision, financial fraud, gambling addiction detection, lifetime value prediction. My aim is to turn abstract knowledge into real world application and solving tools. I am an open minded nerd who act to stay sharp in his domain trough helping other (top 1% on Stackoverflow in 2021), competitions (Kaggle competition expert) and open source contributions. And even if I am clearly driven by the data science field, I also defend the #1 Google ML Rule "Don't be afraid to launch a product without machine learning".

Work Experience _____

Betclic Group Bordeaux, France

DATA SCIENTIST

· Anti Money Laundering detection.

- · Responsible gambling (addiction behavior) detection.
- · Personalized offers for emailing campaign.
- Lifetime value prediction.

Using: Pandas, Scikit-learn, Pytorch, Tensorflow2/Keras, Shap, Airflow, AWS, Unittest/Pytest, Great Expectation...

Cdiscount Bordeaux, France

DATA SIENTIST ADVISOR Nov. 2018 - Mai. 2019

- Massive customer clustering.
- · Bot detection (pattern analysis).
- · Sentiment analysis (Natural Langage Processing).
- Object detection in picture (Mask-RCNN, COCO dataset).

Bordeaux, France

Cdiscount

DATA SIENTIST

- · Search engine relevance.
- · Recommendation engine.
- · Algorithms evaluation (A/B testing). · Focus on website's KPI improvment.
- Python development (Scikit-learn, Numpy, Pandas, Scipy, Luigi etc).
- Hadoop Hive & SQL Databases.

Cdiscount Bordeaux, France

DATA SIENTIST INTERN Mar. 2016 - Sep. 2016

- · Marketing targeting: behavioral analysis and improvment of the search engine relevence through AB test, proof of concept personnalisation client (classification and clustering).
- Geographical data: Purchase forecasting by geographic zone.
- · Statistical analysis: data enrichment with INSEE database, implementation and developement of geocoding tool.
- · Intern innovation contest: Setting of a new operationnal service for the client, forcasting system of product storage to allow express delivery.

Idaia Group Bordeaux, France

DATA SIENTIST INTERN

Jun. 2015 - Aug. 2015

Sep. 2014 - Jul. 2016

Jun 2019 - current

Oct. 2016 - Oct. 2018

· Sourcing, implementation and development of machine learning tools (mainly multiclass classification) in Python and Scala into Apache Spark large-scale data framework.

Education

Toulon University

Bordeaux University Bordeaux, France

MSC. APPLIED MATHEMATICS • Optimization, operation research, machine learning, statistics, C++, Python, SQL.

Toulon, France

Toulon University

BSC. APPLIED MATHEMATICS Sep. 2011 - Jul. 2012

• Statistics, probability, econometry, R, Matlab/Octave.

Toulon, France BSC. PURE MATHEMATICS Sep. 2008 - Jul. 2011

· Algebra, analysis, topology, mesure theory, graph theory, C, Matlab/Octave, Wolfram Mathematica.